(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E04 =- Carol's.Article =- Subripped by zerox
麦克，叫妹妹下来吃饭
Mike, would you get your sister, please?
次货，吃饭!
Yo, Fido, dinner!
水龙头，我来了!
I'll be right down, Fire Hydrant!
告诉妈妈我要写完这一段
Tell Mom I'm just gonna finish this paragraph!
-妈妈，那个次货说要写完那段话 -谢谢，听见了
- Mom, Fido's gonna finish her paragraph. - Thank you, I heard.
水龙头，老实说.
And frankly, Fire Hydrant...
称呼妹妹为“次货”一点也不好玩
I don't think it's funny or appropriate for you to call your sister Fido.
对，那是男孩的绰号
You're right. It's a boy's name.
还在写那篇文章？
Is she still working on that article?
她很看重这次的学校报社征稿
Well, she's taking this tryout for the school paper very seriously.
爸爸，我们说的是.
Come on, Dad, this is the Wait Whitman Chronicle here...
这是“世界有名”的报纸
one of the world's great papers.
名字可是响当当的
It's right up there with Charmin and Nice'n Soft.
麦克，这事对凯罗来说很重要
Mike, this is very important to Carol.
挖苦的话要减少到极点
Try to keep your snide comments to a minimum.
怎样？减少到3句？4句？
So, like, what? Three or four?
宝贝，这样太辛苦了
You're working awfully hard, sweetheart.
我要尽量写好
Yeah, well, I just want to get it right.
要写出质量最好的稿子
You know, so it's, like, the best article they've ever gotten.
很难打败上周的报道：
Pretty tough to beat last weeks scoop:
"Granola bars replace gummy bears in snack machine."
这算一句
That's one.
一句什么？
One what?
妈妈说吃饭时不能超过4句挖苦
Snide comments. Mom says Mike can make three more at you during dinner.
刚才应该是最后一句了，对不对？
I think probably that was the last one. Right, Mike?
是的，爸爸
Why, yes, Father, I believe it was.
明天就见分晓
Anyway, tomorrow's the moment of truth.
明天西蒙老师会阅读所有文章 并决定聘请谁
Tomorrow Mr. Simmons reads all the articles and decides who gets the job.
不是西蒙老师吧？
Oh, no, not Simmons.
西蒙老师是谁？
Why? Who's Simmons?
少写了一个双引号就把学生关起来那个
That's the teacher who locked a kid in a closet for not closing a quote.
宝贝，用不着担心
Well, honey, I don't think you have anything to worry about.
只要尽了力，他肯定会欣赏
Just do the best you can, and I'm sure he'll be impressed.
太兴奋了，印刷机的轰隆声
This is so exciting! The roar of the mighty presses.
我的血液充满了墨水
Ink coursing through my veins.
也许胜任，也许不能
Maybe I've got what it takes, maybe I don"t...
但不全力以赴的话是不会知道的
but I'll never find out if I don't leap into the darkness and give it my all!
她继续下去的话我会吐的
If she sings I Gotta Be Me, I swear I'll throw up.
第2句
That's two.
妈妈.
Mom...
今晚能否批阅一下，说说看法
do you think you could read my article tonight and tell me what you think?
宝贝，我非常乐意
Why, I'd be happy to, honey.
实话实说？
You'll be honest?
铁面无私
Savagely honest.
也许是我多虑了
I know. I'm probably just worrying for nothing, but...
你试过这样全心全意 追求一样东西没有？
have you ever wanted something so much, you could feel it with your entire body?
你不说我还真不知道.
Well, now that you mention it....
好吧，我押20块
Yeah, Jerry. Yeah, put me in for $20.
对，我当然有20块
Yeah, of course I have it.
连20块也没有，这不是人渣是什么？
Look, only a scuzzball wouldn't have $20. Yeah, okay. Bye.
本，借我20块
Hey, Ben, give me $20.
没门
No way.
本，本来不想告诉你.
Ben, we didn't want you to know this...
妈妈需要做手术
but, well, Mom needs an operation.
麦克，这个谎话水平也太没水准了
That's low, Mike, even for you.
好吧，杰里在赛马场
Okay, okay, okay. Look, Jerry Dellish is over at Off-Track Betting...
他有第4场“极度难喝”的内幕消息
and hes got a hot tip on Pesky Persky in the fourth.
“极度难喝”是马名？
Is that a horse?
当然是马，难道是啤酒？
No, it's an imported beer. Of course it's a horse.
我是给你机会赢100块
Ben, look, I'm giving you the opportunity to make $100.
听起来不错
That sounds pretty good.
当然不错
Of course it sounds pretty good...
别一副被我强暴的表情
and you're acting like I'm trying to put one over on you or something.
对不起
I'm sorry.
算了吧，你干不干？
Look, forget it. But you'll do it?
当然了，赢了大家分钱
Sure, and well split the profits.
好的
All right, Ben.
-我70，你30 -什么？
- 70-30, mine. - What?
不要就算了
Take it or leave it.
好吧，好吧.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
合作愉快，麦克
It's a pleasure doing business with you, Mike.
这孩子非池中物
That kids gonna be good.
凯罗的文章不至于这样吧？
Carol's paper can't be that bad.
她写的是挖蚌的人
She wrote about guys who dig for clams.
有什么不好？
Well, what's wrong with that?
题目是
She called it, "l Clam, Therefore I Am."
她还在挖？
Did she now?
听听看.
Listen to this:
“日暮苍穹曜石峡..”
"Night obduces the isthmus neath its obsidian mantle.
“蛤蜊张壳海水呷”
"The mollusks imbibe one last sip twixt their vaI'ves...
“黏液仍在颊”
"and expel the days muculence."
是夸张了一点
She could be pushing a little.
杰森，你自己看
Jason, read this.
“挖蚌人像六指琴魔，七上八下..”
"With dexterous manipulation of his digits, the master clammer...
“把润滑的软体动物..”
"extricates the muculent mollusk...
“从青金石下揪了出来”
"from its lapideous menage."
这样看吧.
Well, look at it this way.
我们的女儿知道什么是软体动物
We have a daughter who knows what muculence is.
有多少人知道什么是软体动物？
How many people know what muculence is?
没有人知道，这也是问题所在
Nobody knows what muculence is, and that's the problem.
报刊文章应该写得一目了然
Newspaper writing needs to be clear, accessible.
杰森，我该怎么说？ 她需要我实话实说
Jason, what am I gonna tell her? She asked for my honest opinion.
哪个孩子能接受实话？
No kid want's your honest opinion.
她们需要无条件的支持
They want unconditional approval.
要是不赞成呢？
And what if you don't approve?
那样就会进退两难，像现在这样
Then you have a significant dilemma, much like the one you're in now.
谢谢你，西弗医生
Thank you, Dr. Seaver.
拜托帮帮忙
Come on, Jason. Help me out here.
这次就当作学习的机会
Well, look, we want this to be a learning experience for her.
-继续 -学习是基于.
- Go on. - And all learning is based...
-我们正面的鼓励 -继续
- on positive reinforcement. - More.
有如训练鸽子，你要赏它一颗小球
See, if you want a pigeon to perform, you reward it with a pellet.
什么意思？
What are you saying?
我说我们应该养鸽子，鸽子比人好养
I'm saying we should have had pigeons. They're easier to raise.
杰森，别逗了
Jason, come on.
一开始指出文章的长处.
You just start off by pointing out the strengths of the article...
接着你示范如何改进
and then you show her how the article could be improved.
说得对
You're right.
-突出优点 -对
- Accentuate the positive. - Yes.
要婉转，同情，热情
Be gentle and nurturing and supportive.
若不行的话.
Then, if that doesn't work...
把她绑起来，烧掉她的名贵球鞋
you simply tie her to the bed and set her Reeboks on fire.
凯罗？
Carol?
进来
Come in.
这么晚你一定是累了，明天再谈
Well, it's late. You must be tired. We can talk about this in the morning.
不，我在等着你呢
No, no, I've been waiting for you.
我把文章又看了一遍 现在能够更客观了
I've read the article again, and I think I can be more objective now.
把文章搁下来一段时间，这样做很好
Well, that's a good thing to do. Put it away for a while, get some distance.
-接着就会发现之前完美的地方.. -我知道，已经改了
- Often what you thought was perfect-- - I know, I know. I already changed it.
是吗？
You did?
是的
Yeah.
软体动物这词出现了两次，太糟糕了
The two "muculences" in the same sentence. Terrible.
我把第二个改成“贝壳类动物”
I made the second one "pituitousness."
噢!
Oh!
骄傲吧？说实话
Are you proud of me, Mom? The truth.
不错，我为你而骄傲
Of course. Honey, I am always proud of you.
我能成为记者？
You think I'll make the paper?
显然你有潜力
Well, it's obvious you have potential.
能写出这种文章的人.
Very few people could write like...
少之又少
this.
那我就不用做任何改动了
So you don't think I should change anything. Mom, this is great.
这个.
Well...
我要说的是.
what I'm saying is...
这篇文章你花了很长的时间
Carol, it's clear that you put a lot of time into this article.
构思很好
It's well thought out.
打字清晰
It's well typed.
还有这些边框格式很好
And I just love these margins.
但是呢？
But?
也不用接一个“但是”
Well, it's not so much a "but"....
听起来你要说“但是”
It sounds just like a "but."
我要说的是.
Well, what I'm trying to say is--
说出“但是”什么吧
Cut to the "but, " Mom.
但是.
But...
这不适合报章
it's just not newspaper writing, honey.
每个领域都有规矩
Look, in any field there are rules.
你学学就懂的了
You just have to learn them.
报刊文章应该简单明了，开门见山
Newspaper writing has to be more simple, straightforward.
你认为我的文章是垃圾
So you think my articles garbage.
宝贝.
Sweetheart...
若是交给西蒙老师.
if I let you turn this in to Mr. Simmons...
他也会如是说，只会更严厉
He'd tell you the same things, only meaner.
"Introduction to Journalism."
这对我很有帮助，相信对你也是
I found it very helpful, and I'm sure you will, too.
是的
Yeah.
没事吧？
Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
真的？
Really?
真的，谢谢你的意见
Yeah, really. Thanks for your advice.
很好
Good.
宝贝，晚安
Good night, pumpkin.
"Introduction to Journalism."
杰里说第8场应该买浪涛那匹马
I know. Jerry says we bet on Undulate in the eighth.
应该买霸王那匹
I say we bet on Arbitrary.
-为什么？ -不为什么
- Why? - Why not?
本，瞧瞧这些纪录
Ben, look at these times.
等到霸王过终点 恐怕你胸毛都长出来了
I mean, you'll be growing chest hair before Arbitrary finishes this race.
我这次有预感
I just got a hunch about this one.
本，押注不能靠预感
Ben, you cant bet a race on a hunch.
但是霸王最近4场比赛的情形.
Okay, what about that Arbitrary comes out of Secretariat by way of Seabiscuit...
跟里描述的故事很像
and Alonzo picked up three purses in his last four turf outings?
这个我知道，我们还是相信杰里吧
Hey, I know that, but I say we stick with Jerry.
他到目前为止都很准
I mean, hes been right so far.
我不太放心
I'm not so sure.
关系是谁拉过来的？
Ben, who's got the connections?
钱是谁的？
Who's got the money?
我俩谁有体重优势？
Who's got the weight advantage?
买那匹浪涛!
Go, Undulate!
醒醒好吗？
Earth to Maggie.
没事吧？
Everything okay?
Oh.
凯罗为什么还不下来
Well, I was just wondering why Carol hasn't come down yet.
但愿、昨晚我没有太严厉
I hope I wasn't too hard on her last night.
你肯定没有…
No, I'm sure you were just....
除非…
Unless....
你真的烧掉她的球鞋？
Did you burn her Reeboks?
妈妈，圣诞节要什么礼物 我有的是钱
What do you want for Christmas, Mom? Cause my middle name is Money.
如果没记错的话
Correct me if I'm wrong...
你是本.汉弗莱.西弗吧？
but I've been living under the assumption your middle name was Humphrey.
我讨厌这个名字 我有65块，应该够改名字了
I hate Humphrey, and a kid with $65 can call his own shots.
是吗？
Really?
哪来的65块？
Ben, where did you get $65?
我和麦克.
Well, me and Mike--
是我挣到了钱 你们教导我做人要行善好施
I came into a little money, Mom, and you've always taught me to share...
于是我和弟弟一起分享
so I'm sharing it with my little bro.
麦克，别瞎编了 说实话
And now, just for the heck of it, Mike, the truth.
杰里帮我们买马，赢了
Jerry Dellish bet on a horse for us, and we won.
麦克，你拿本的钱去赌博？
Mike, you took Ben's money and risked it on a horse?
杰里说肯定会赢的
It was a sure thing, Mom. Jerry Dellish said so.
那个花心的杰里？
Jerry "l-swear-she-looked-18" Dellish?
以后不准再赌
There will be no more betting.
-但是我们赢了 -妈妈…
- But, Mom, we won! - Mom--
-杰里… -等等…
- Jerry-- - But wait. But, Mom...
他们运气来了，赢马了…
these guys are hot. They're on a roll. They won.
当然也有不少人在赛马场输钱…
Now I'm sure there are some people who actually lose money at the track...
因为他们不认识杰里
but those people don't know Jerry Dellish.
杰森，或许你说得对
Well, maybe you're right, Jason.
孩子们有把握赢钱
These boys do seem to have "winner" written all over them.
那么第8场可以买那匹浪涛了？
So we can let it ride on Undulate in the eighth?
孩子们，站在朋友的角度…
Boys, and I say this to you as a friend...
我说不押就傻了
I think you'd be crazy not to.
-太好了 -我们要赢了
- Yeah, all right! - Were in the money.
-谢谢，再见 -要赢钱了
- Thanks a lot. See you later. - Were in the money.
别着急，我的办法可行
Don't worry, this will work.
我赌2块
$2 says you're a loser.
-好吧 -奉陪
- You're on. - Okay.
凯罗？
Carol?
别担心，她没事
Don't worry, she'll be fine.
西弗家的人，受得起批评
After all, she is a Seaver. She can take criticism. Okay?
凯罗，早上好
Good morning, Carol.
-真漂亮 -谢谢
- You look nice. - Thank you.
这毛衣很好看
That's a real cute sweater.
喜欢吗？
You like it?
很喜欢，颜色亲托出你的大眼睛
A lot. It's a good color for you. It brings out your eyes.
不会太鲜艳吗？
It's not too bright?
很相称
It's very becoming.
不然我可要找书看了，例如…
You sure? If not, I imagine theres a book I could read...
perhaps Introduction to Dressing?
这也叫做事实？
You call these facts?
有多少学生吃过鱼肉后呕吐了？
How many kids threw up from the tuna casserole?
饭堂那边的说法是怎样的？
And where is the cafeterias side of the story?
饭堂表示无可奉告
Food Services had no comment.
“饭堂无可奉告”
"Food Services had no comment."
马上回到饭堂采访
You go back down to the cafeteria.
听听做三明治和布丁的人的看法
Somebody in sandwiches or in pudding has an ax to grind.
自己好好想想，再写一份
You find yourself a Deep Throat, and you bring back a story.
下一个
Next.
坐下
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
凯罗？
Carol, eh?
想当记者？批准
All right, you want the job? You got it.
真的？你喜欢我的文章？ 我花了许多时间在比喻那里
Really? You like my writing? I worked so hard on my metaphors.
你的比喻太臭了
Metaphors stink.
-明喻的地方… -明喻也太臭了
- Similes are more-- - Similes stink.
你的文章太臭了
Your writing, it stinks.
什么？
What?
不好意思，我忘记在和谁说话了
Excuse me, I forgot who I was talking to.
一股腐臭的味道充斥着这篇文章
It is replete with stinkiosity.
不过至少你没写错字，他们错字百出
But at least you can spell. The others, they cant even spell.
你却写出了没有人懂的词
But you spell words that nobody knows.
软体动物!
Muculence!
究竟什么叫做软体动物？
What in the hell is muculence?
那个…
Well, its....
基本上…
It's basically...
就是蚌
slimy glop.
那直接写蚌就好了
Then you call it slimy glop!
大家都知道什么是蚌
People know what slimy glop is.
-可是我认为… -“认为”这词不适合这里
- Yeah, well, I just felt that maybe it was-- - Felt is for pool tables.
周一开始工作
You start Monday.
谢谢，我不要这份工作了
Well, thank you, but I don't think I want the job.
远处拐弯，小姑娘领先
Around the far turn, it's Nice Girl in the lead.
-浪涛，加油! -浪涛，加油!
- Come on, Undulate! - Come on, Undulate!
小姑娘领先修门人6个马位
It's still Nice Girl a full six lengths ahead of Hedge Trimmer...
浪涛远远落后
with Undulate a distant third.
浪涛可能要落下了
Hey, guys, it looks like Undulates gonna be very late.
别急，小姑娘前期太用力，后劲不足
Relax. Nice Girl always starts strong. Shell fade.
小姑娘后劲不足
And Nice Girl's starting to fade.
浪涛，加油!
Now, come on, you can do it, Undulate.
别着急，它会从外围超越
Don't worry. She'll make her move on the outside, right here.
浪涛从外围赶上
And let's see, moving on the outside, it's Undulate.
瞧它的驰骋!最后冲刺了
Look at her go! And they're moving down the final stretch.
齐头并进，小姑娘，浪涛
They're neck and neck. It's Nice Girl, Undulate.
小姑娘，浪涛
Nice Girl, Undulate.
冲线了.
And at the finish, it's...
浪涛险胜
Undulate! By a nose hair.
赔率是1赔9
And she'll pay off at nine to one, folks.
-1赔9 -天哪!是450大洋
- Nine to one? - Holy cow! That's $450.
一定是杰里从马场打来 我们怎么办？
All right, that's Jerry calling from OTB. What do we do, Fast Benny?
收下450块还是押到第9场的吞噬者？
We keep the $450 or let it ride on Nail Biter in the ninth?
孩子们，我认为应该激流勇退
You guys, I think you should quit while you're ahead.
杰森!
Jason!
麦姬，450块啊，存进银行 算算利息.
Maggie, it's $450. You put that in a rollover account, with interest the way....
拜托
Come on.
我们下次再教育他们吧，好吧
We could teach them this gambling lesson another time, you know. Okay.
孩子们，当运气好时，应该乘胜追击
Boys, I say this is no time to stop. You know, you got it. You got that touch.
好吧，杰里，全部买吞噬者
All right, Jerry, put it all on Nail Biter to win.
凯罗，西蒙老师怎么说了
Hi, Carol. How did it go with Simmons?
很好，他聘用我了
Fine, thank you. I got the job.
真的.
Oh, really? Well....
宝贝，恭喜你，太好了
Well, congratulations, honey. That's wonderful.
凯罗当上记者了
Carol got the job on the paper.
作家!作家!
Author, author.
我拒绝了
I turned it down.
可以进来吗？
Can I come in?
可以
Sure.
在干嘛？
What are you doing?
清理垃圾
Cleaning this garbage out of my way.
凯罗，怎么拒绝这次机会了？
Carol, how come you turned the job down?
你不是一心要当记者吗？
I mean, it really seemed like you had your heart set on it.
那时候我还没意识到.
Yeah, well, that was before I realized...
报刊文章不需要创造性
theres nothing really creative about journalism.
只不过是堆砌事实
I mean, all you do is regurgitate facts.
要写作的话，我宁愿、写小说
If I were going to be a writer, I'd rather do a novel.
至少没有人会模仿
At least people don't train their puppies on Moby-Dick.
凯罗，我知道批评了你.
Carol, I can understand you being angry at me...
你在生我的气
for my criticism of your article.
犯不着生气，西蒙老师通过了
Why should I be angry? Simmons gave me the job.
我知道
I know.
我要说的是.
I know, and I guess what I'm trying to say is....
批评心爱的人是一件很难的事情
Well, honey, it's always tricky giving criticism to someone you love...
也许我的做法不够妥当
and I guess I just didn't do a very good job.
西蒙老师很赞赏你的写法
Obviously, Simmons was very happy with what you did...
我庆幸我错了
and I'm glad that I was wrong.
不是的
No.
什么？
Pardon me?
我说不是的，高兴了吧？ 他的话跟你大致一样，只是更严厉
I said no, okay? Are you happy? He said everything you said, only worse.
他说我的文章.
He said my article was...
“充斥着一股腐臭的气味”
"replete with stinkiosity."
你不是说通过了吗？
But you said that you got the job.
是的，因为其它文章更加臭气熏天
Yeah, that was only cause all the other articles were repleter with stinkiosity.
真遗憾
Honey, I am so sorry.
他说他不知道什么是软体动物
He said he didn't even know what muculence was.
那.
Well, that's....
那是他孤陋寡闻
That's just his stupidity, sweetheart.
大家都认识软体动物
Everybody knows what muculence is.
我永远也不能像你那样写作
I'll never be able to write like you.
等等，不是的
Hold on. Hold on, honey. That's just not true.
你也许会感到有点.
Now maybe you were reaching a little...
但是你有天分
but you have great natural ability.
你只是安慰我
You're just saying that.
你不记得昨天的事了？
Didn't I establish myself last night...
我并不害怕说真话
as someone who isn't afraid to tell the truth?
是的
Yeah.
尽管会让一个小孩子心碎
Even if it does mean crushing a little kids ego.
你真的认为我有天分？
Do you really think I might have natural ability?
这是下午从阁楼找到的
I dug this out of the attic this afternoon.
你要看看吧？
And I thought that you might like to take a look at it.
五年前夏令营时我的家信
The letter I wrote from camp five years ago?
念念
Read it.
“亲爱的爸爸妈妈，夏令营很好玩”
"Dear Mom and Dad, camp is fun.
“除了观察毒漆藤时 我得了红诊这一点”
"Except for the rash I got when I tried to find out what poison sumac looks like.
“除了大家取笑我是左撇子 长得矮这一点”
"Except for the kids teasing anyone who's small or fat or left-handed.
还有想念你和本宝宝
"Except for missing you and baby Ben.
“甚至有点想念麦克，但别告诉他”
"And even Mike a little, but don't tell him.
“探望我记得带上我的实验设备和薯条”
"Bring my chemistry set and potato chips on visiting day.
“凯罗字”
"Love, Carol."
写得不大好
That's not so good.
我们把实验设备和薯条都带去了
Didn't we bring your chemistry set and your potato chips?
是的
Yeah.
那么就是言简意骇
Then you got your point across.
是的
Yeah.
我懂你意思了
Yeah, I see what you're saying.
很好
Good.
不过还能写得更好
But I still think it could have been better.
还能怎么写？
Now, what makes you say that?
写上千万别把麦克带来
Well, as I remember, you brought Mike, too.
真是不可思议
And this is unbelievable.
最后的拐弯，吞噬者领先18个马位
Coming around the final turn, it's Nail Biter by 18 lengths.
第二名青蛙远远落后
Running a distant second is Slim's Frog...
还有阿诺之梦在第三位
with Arnold's Dream Date in third position.
-吞噬者! -吞噬者!
- Nail Biter! - Yeah, Nail Biter!
-吞噬者领先20个马位 -吞噬者，冲啊!
- And it's Nail Biter by 20 lengths. - Go, Nail Biter!
吞噬者最后冲刺，领先25个马位
And Nail Biter's at the final pole, and he must be a full 25 lengths ahead.
走路过去也能赢了
That horse could walk in from here.
吞噬者!冲!以后我就衣食无忧了
Go, Nail Biter! I'll never have to work again!
各位且慢，突发意外
Ladies and gentlemen, wait a minute. There's been an accident.
吞噬者坠马倒地
Nail Biter has tripped and gone down. The horse is on the ground.
赛马这么久我还没见过坠马呢
In all my years at the track, I've never seen anything like this.
-起来!起来! -起来!
- Get up, get up! - Get up!
离终点只剩1尺
A foot from the finish line, maybe two feet...
骑师企图把马拉过终点
and the jockey is trying to drag the horse across the finish.
-快抬起来 -真是壮观!
- Well, pick him up and carry him. - This is amazing.
90斤重的人抓住马腿要拖动一匹马
A 94-pound man trying to drag a racehorse by one leg!
他个子太小了
Hes too small!
-使劲!使劲! -笨蛋，用力!
- Pull him! Pull him! - Come on, you little munchkin, grab him!
小心，外围青蛙追上来了
Look out! Coming up on the outside is Slim's Frog.
第一名是青蛙
And the winner is Slim's Frog!
真是的.
It was just....
你们知道教训了吧
I hope you boys have learned your lesson.
瞧瞧
Look it here.
X光照出吞噬者腓骨骨折
"X-rays reveal that Nail Biter suffered a fractured fibula.
教练立刻宣布.
"Trainer Jim Shepherd immediately announced...
这匹纯种马将会变成种马
"that his prize thoroughbred would be put out to stud."
什么是种马？
What's stud?
妈妈
Mom.
有时候公马受了伤.
Well, Ben, sometimes when a boy horse gets hurt...
那么它就要帮许多母马受孕
they use him to get lots and lots of girl horses pregnant.
很好
That's very good.
我的腿!
My leg!
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.03.12